<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HPC on Technical Computing Goulash</title>
    <link>http://gpsamu.github.io/tags/hpc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in HPC on Technical Computing Goulash</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>UTF-8</language>
    <copyright>Gábor Samu - All rights reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 11:37:03 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://gpsamu.github.io/tags/hpc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cool and quiet benchmarking on MACCHIATObin (Armada 8040)</title>
      <link>http://gpsamu.github.io/blog/benchmarking_macchiatobin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2017 11:37:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gpsamu.github.io/blog/benchmarking_macchiatobin/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve recently taken delivery of a few new goodies to complement the MACCHIATObin Arm v8 powered board that I&#39;ve written about recently on my blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standing up a IBM Spectrum LSF Community Edition cluster on Arm v8</title>
      <link>http://gpsamu.github.io/blog/spectrumlsf_armv8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 12:01:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gpsamu.github.io/blog/spectrumlsf_armv8/</guid>
      <description>So, you&#39;ve got yourself a shiny new (or maybe not) system based upon a 64-bit Arm (Arm v8) processor that you want to put through it&#39;s paces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oh Woe is 2016 - NOT!</title>
      <link>http://gpsamu.github.io/blog/woe_is_2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2017 16:17:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gpsamu.github.io/blog/woe_is_2016/</guid>
      <description>As we enter a new year, 2016 seems to have been tarnished it the closing month by events around the world. Far be it for me to to talk about world events here, I’d like to focus on the good - at least from my perspective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SC16: Stir it up!</title>
      <link>http://gpsamu.github.io/blog/sc16_stiritup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 19:54:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gpsamu.github.io/blog/sc16_stiritup/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s been ages since I&#39;ve posted to this blog. I&#39;ve not forgotten about it - I&#39;ve been figuratively stirring the technical computing goulash pot over on the IBM Systems In the Making blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reminiscing and the computing renaissance</title>
      <link>http://gpsamu.github.io/blog/reminiscing_computingrenaissance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 20:44:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gpsamu.github.io/blog/reminiscing_computingrenaissance/</guid>
      <description>Sifting through boxes of 3.5 inch floppy diskettes - some of questionable provenance in a dusty basement. Gingerly packing up what I consider to be the holy trinity of Commodore Amiga computers - A1000, A2000, A3000 - all in some state of working condition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking back at ISC High-Performance 2015</title>
      <link>http://gpsamu.github.io/blog/isc15_lookingback/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2015 21:08:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gpsamu.github.io/blog/isc15_lookingback/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve always enjoyed a good road trip. There&#39;s just something fun about jumping in the car, and heading to a far off location. As they say, half of the fun is just getting to your destination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IBM Platform Cluster Manager - how do you like your eggs?</title>
      <link>http://gpsamu.github.io/blog/clustermanager_eggs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2015 21:42:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gpsamu.github.io/blog/clustermanager_eggs/</guid>
      <description>Whether your HPC center is in Lilliput or Blefuscu, you&#39;ll appreciate the importance of a flexible and easy-to-use cluster management solution to empower your populations. Administrators need software that will allow them to easily setup, manage, monitor and maintain their infrastructure and ensure consistency for repeatable performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IBM Platform LSF and Docker: A Whale of a time!</title>
      <link>http://gpsamu.github.io/blog/lsf_docker_whale/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2015 21:49:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gpsamu.github.io/blog/lsf_docker_whale/</guid>
      <description>Containers are useful. Whether you&#39;re shipping things across the blue seas or encapsulating applications on a computer system, they provide numerous benefits. HPC Administrators will know that applications today can depend upon multiple packages, libraries and environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IBM Software Defined Infrastructure: Put the POWER down and jump the chasm! </title>
      <link>http://gpsamu.github.io/blog/sdi_openpower/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2015 09:24:34 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gpsamu.github.io/blog/sdi_openpower/</guid>
      <description>OpenPOWER continues to put the power down and accelerate strongly in 2015.
Earlier this year, the First Annual OpenPOWER Summit took place and more recently Cabot Partners published the paper Crossing the Performance Chasm with OpenPOWER, outlining the benefits of OpenPOWER for HPC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HPC: Seeing is believing</title>
      <link>http://gpsamu.github.io/blog/hpc_seeing_believing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 09:34:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gpsamu.github.io/blog/hpc_seeing_believing/</guid>
      <description>People who know me, know that I like to tinker. Whether it’s with cars, computers or other mechanical gizmos, I’ve always enjoyed dismantling and reassembling things - understanding what makes them tick.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker for HPC</title>
      <link>http://gpsamu.github.io/blog/docker_for_hpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2014 10:21:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gpsamu.github.io/blog/docker_for_hpc/</guid>
      <description>With the recent release of Docker 1.0 and the broad industry backing from organizations such as Red Hat and IBM, it&#39;s no wonder that interest in the use and application of this Linux container technology continues to grow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISC 2014: Auf Wiedersehen Leipzig</title>
      <link>http://gpsamu.github.io/blog/isc14_leipzig/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2014 10:24:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gpsamu.github.io/blog/isc14_leipzig/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve just returned from International Supercomputing 2014, which took place in Leipzig, Germany. As was the case in 2013, I greatly enjoyed my time at the conference, and the hospitality in Leipzig.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Armed and ready with IBM Platform LSF</title>
      <link>http://gpsamu.github.io/blog/armed_ready_lsf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2014 10:39:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gpsamu.github.io/blog/armed_ready_lsf/</guid>
      <description>These days it&#39;s not uncommon to hear about CPUs based upon ARM cores. They can be found in mobile phones, embedded systems, laptops and even servers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IBM Platform HPC V4.1.1.1: Best Practices for Managing NVIDIA GPU devices</title>
      <link>http://gpsamu.github.io/blog/hpc411_nvidia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2013 13:35:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gpsamu.github.io/blog/hpc411_nvidia/</guid>
      <description>Summary
IBM Platform HPC V4.1.1.1 is easy-to-use, yet comprehensive technical computing infrastructure management software. It includes as standard GPU management capabilities including monitoring and workload scheduling for systems equipped with NVIDIA GPU devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IBM Platform HPC 4.1.1: Creating a network bridge on compute nodes</title>
      <link>http://gpsamu.github.io/blog/hpc411_bridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2013 13:12:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gpsamu.github.io/blog/hpc411_bridge/</guid>
      <description>Applies to
 IBM Platform HPC V4.1.1 IBM Platform Cluster Manager V4.1.1  Introduction
IBM Platform HPC provides the ability to customise the network configuration of compute nodes via Network Profiles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISC 2013 wrapup: IBM Platform HPC and Intel Xeon Phi </title>
      <link>http://gpsamu.github.io/blog/isc13_wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2013 11:58:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gpsamu.github.io/blog/isc13_wrapup/</guid>
      <description>This past June at ISC 2013 the IBM booth featured live demonstration of IBM Platform HPC V3.2 managing an IBM iDataplex cluster equipped with Intel Xeon Phi coprocessors.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>